♪Memories hold you back
from fulfilling your dreams♪
♪Only by moving forward
can you find reunion♪
♪Endings only mark new routes♪
♪It's all part of the scenery♪
♪To the horizon's call♪
♪Your journey hasn't started♪
♪Towards mountains,
chase the stars bright♪
♪Let time embrace you
and wash away the past♪
♪Put every twist behind you♪
♪Drift leisurely through time♪
♪Make headway against the wind♪
♪Let mountains bow to your pace♪
♪Rush towards a life without regret♪
♪Let your nature burst free♪
=The First Jasmine=
=Episode 15=
Put it aside.
What happened?
A ghost!
I fell into the pond.
Something grabbed my foot.
Such great strength!
I couldn't shake it off at all.
It's her!
Shut up.
In this world, there is no ghost.
Don't talk nonsense here
and mislead people.
It's true, Uncle Wending.
There really is a ghost.
Alright.
Ying, enough.
You're just too terrified. Enough.
You must be tangled by water plants.
I...
It's so late.
Why weren't you two
resting in your rooms,
but staying by the pond?
I asked her to go.
Although I took back Shende Shop,
business hasn't picked up.
I wanted to host a ladies' banquet,
inviting the noble ladies
from all mansions
in the capital to promote Shende Shop.
She knows the preferences
of the noble ladies,
so I asked her to help me host it.
Host a banquet?
When did you two become
so close and support each other?
We are sisters connected by blood.
And now both of us
have married a prince.
We share honor and disgrace.
If we don't support each other,
should we undermine each other,
letting outsiders make fun of us?
The color of this skeleton has faded.
This is definitely not a recent death.
I'm afraid it's been
soaking in water for some years.
Who is it exactly?
- Yeah.
- When pulled out of the water,
there were stones tied to this skeleton.
No wonder it never floated up.
This was intended to keep her
at the bottom of the water forever.
Such an atrocity!
This is clearly a murder case.
In my opinion, we should report this
and let the officials investigate.
What? Absurd!
Well...
This skeleton has been there for years.
Is it that easy to investigate?
Who knows what old stories
it might stir up?
Listen, all of you.
This matter ends here tonight.
No more discussion.
Do not spread a single word
outside the mansion.
Do you hear me?
Tonight, no one is allowed
to leave the mansion.
Arrange for the elders to go rest.
Yes.
Then what should we do
with the skeleton?
Go rest.
The ancestors have blessings,
so naturally they are not afraid.
But it's not certain
whether we can rest properly.
After all, a tragic death
breeds resentment.
What if something comes
to haunt us at midnight?
She won't.
She is Yanlu, my mother's
personal maid back then.
Yanlu? Which Yanlu?
There's such a maid in the mansion?
Uncle Wending, don't you remember Yanlu?
Back then, you broke into
my mother's courtyard
and took her things.
Yanlu was injured by you when she tried
to protect my mother's belongings.
Later, your men carried her away,
saying they would treat her wounds.
But now?
She's dead.
And her body was found in the pond
of our Ye family garden,
even with stones tied to it.
Shut up.
How can you identify
a person from just bones?
That's not Yanlu at all.
I might not recognize her well,
but I recognize this bracelet.
This is what my mother
personally awarded her back then.
When I was little, Yanlu often
took it off for me to play with.
I remember
the twined branch pattern on it clearly.
Tell me. Why did she die?
Did you kill her?
You not only caused my mother's death,
but you also harmed a loyal maid
who protected my mother?
Ridiculous! Your mother Xu Wanzhou
returned to Lishan Mountain with you.
She's dead?
She is already dead.
Uncle Wending, do you really not know?
Father, haven't you told him yet?
She is already dead.
And you are all murderers.
Mo Xiuwen was already
a death-row prisoner at that time,
a confirmed rebel.
Your mother was just a woman,
yet she's not well-behaved,
and colluded with a court rebel
like Mo Xiuwen,
attempting to stir up trouble
and dragging
the entire Ye family into it.
Did she want us
to be buried with that rebel?
The Ye family cast her out,
to cut our losses and seek survival.
It was not only to save the lives
of our clan, over a hundred people,
but also to give her a way out.
A way out?
Is that what you think too, Father?
Did you really do that for her sake?
But right after
Lishan Academy sealed off,
you were afraid of being implicated
and forced her to leave.
Even when she was on her deathbed,
breathing her last.
Did you ever care about her?
Mom!
Mom, hang in there.
General Mo.
Mom, don't scare me.
I'm sorry.
Mom.
My lady.
Stop the carriage.
Physician, please hurry!
Slow down.
Mom.
Because she was too out of touch
to see the situation clearly.
The Empress Dowager
has long had absolute power.
But what about you?
Lishan Academy sealed off the mountain
under the pretext of compiling texts,
offending the current emperor.
So you killed Yanlu?
Nonsense! I didn't.
You pushed her into the water.
Nonsense!
We hired a physician
to save her back then.
She died of severe injuries.
She's destined to have a short life.
You can't blame us for that.
What?
Well said.
Even if she really died of her injuries,
but the Ye family
could not even spare a thin coffin
and a handful of earth
for her?
Her body sank to the bottom
of the pool in the garden,
even with stones tied to it.
If you did nothing wrong,
why would this happen?
You!
You tell me. Was it you
who buried her back then?
Master Wending, it's me.
I buried her. I did bury her!
Well, maybe Ms. Xu and the maid
truly have resentment
- and they've come back to seek justice.
- Come on, don't talk nonsense!
Wanzhou. It must be Wanzhou.
She and Yanlu are blaming us.
They're blaming us.
D-Don't come for us.
D-Don't come for me!
Enough nonsense!
Don't come for me!
Stop this nonsense!
They're dead.
Don't come for me!
Stop it now, or I'll...
Master, something's happened.
Jingzhao Prefecture is searching
the entire capital for some fugitives.
How could this happen?
What is wrong with tonight?
♪The towering Lishan Mountain♪
♪Rises into the sky♪
♪The mighty Lishui River♪
♪Flows ever east♪
Who is playing the guqin there?
It's Wanzhou. Wanzhou is back!
She's back.
You go check.
I'm not going.
Let me see who's playing tricks.
Come on, let's go together.
No way.
I'm not going.
Let's go.
Hurry, Father.
I'm not going.
- No, no!
- Hurry!
No. I don't want to go!
Don't push me. I don't want to go.
I'm not going.
- Don't be scared.
- I don't want to go.
What are you afraid of?
I...
- There's no ghost in the world.
- I'm not going.
Don't come for me.
I'm not going.
This way.
You wench! Are you
trying to scare us to death?
My lady, I have no idea.
I think I fell asleep and woke up here.
This guqin...
It must be this guqin haunting.
My lady.
Wenhua.
Long time no see.
How are you?
Why didn't you help me back then?
Stay back.
Why?
Give it back.
- Stay back.
- I'm going back to Lishan Mountain.
Away, evil spirits!
Master, save me!
(Jingzhao Prefecture)
Open the door! Hurry! Open up!
Open the door! Open up! Hurry!
(Meng's Incense and Candle Shop)
Your Highness, are you all right?
Your Highness.
You shouldn't come to save me.
So I should just watch
you guys get captured?
Your Highness, my life is worthless.
If I can't break out,
I'll just end myself.
How could I let you take risks?
All these years,
you've been loyal to me.
I can't let anyone else
around me get hurt anymore.
Besides,
our plan has just begun.
I know.
Your Highness,
the entire city is on high alert now.
All the wards are isolated.
The wardens are conducting
a thorough search.
If we can't go back before dawn,
they'll find us sooner or later.
Wending, this is my fault.
Please, everyone, go back and rest.
Get some rest.
Get rest.
I noticed that the evil aura here
is overwhelming
and calculated
that disaster would strike here,
so I came one day early.
I hope I'm not disturbing you.
No. Master, you've come just in time.
Master, evil spirits
have invaded this place.
You saw it too, right?
My wife and all the servants
in the mansion have been possessed.
Master, please save me!
Have you finished folding
the 999 paper golden lotuses
I asked you to?
All done, not a single one missing.
Good.
Then I will set up
a ritual ground for you
to send this uninvited guest
off your mansion.
Heaven's gate opens, Earth's gate opens.
Cinnabar cracks talismans
to startle demons.
Bronze bells shake souls
to subdue the stiff corpses.
The ritual is complete,
but the spirit of the deceased lingers
for a reason.
She might have unfulfilled wishes
in the mortal world.
Mr. Ye.
I presume you know
what this female guest in your mansion
cared about the most when she was alive.
Mr. Ye, do you have anything
you wish to say to your wife?
Give me back
the imperial decree, Wenhua.
We promised General Mo, Wenhua.
Father will be here soon.
Wanzhou.
Wenhua.
I'm sorry for that. I'm sorry.
Wenhua, who sent you here?
I...
I understand it's hard
to speak out your mind.
When you feel like it,
you can pour them out
through the brush.
Past events and old grudges,
all given to this flame.
Don't be sad.
I'm not sad.
My lady.
Don't be afraid.
Come on.
General Wang is a man of honor.
As long as he doesn't
cause trouble for me,
(Jingzhao Prefecture)
I'll let it go.
The weather has changed.
Your Highness, we've checked
several streets around.
Now, only the Ye Mansion
remains unchecked.
Ye Mansion.
(Ye Mansion)
(Mom, let's not go back to the capital.
Can we just stay in Lishan Mountain?)
No, Li. You are
a child of the Ye family.
And I am your father's lawful wife.
Mom, why did you marry Father back then?
Because I love your father.
And does Father love you?
Of course.
Father loves me, and he loves you too.
Who? Who's there?
Someone! Someone come!
Guards!
Wanzhou, listen to me.
I know I did something wrong,
but I had no choice.
Wanzhou, you can't blame me.
You forced me to do so.
You insisted on holding onto that thing.
I did it for the Ye family.
Wanzhou, please spare me.
I'm sorry.
Please, forgive me.
Please, I beg you.
Li.
Mom.
What did you say?
Mom, you're here.
Who are you talking to?
Who's there?
Mom.
Wanzhou.
She's asking you something.
She's asking you.
The decree mobilizing
Heiyun Cavalry to the capital,
who did you give it to?
I...
Dowager Consort Qin.
I knew it.
You and your short-lived mom
are cut from the same cloth.
You're both vengeful spirits
crawling out of the underworld,
coming to bring disaster
upon our Ye family.
You've been faking it all along.
So you are not senile
and forget everything.
I may forget everything,
except the two of you,
mother and daughter.
You jinx, you were born
to ruin the Ye family.
Jinx?
If Mom hadn't married him,
he was just a low-ranking
ninth-grade official.
His household couldn't
even afford a few servants.
It was my mom's dowry
that made your Ye family prosperous.
She tacitly allowed the Ye family
to use Lishan Mountain's name
to pull strings.
Only then did Ye Wenhua
and Ye Wending get promoted.
Have you all forgotten this?
Shut up.
Since she married into the Ye family,
she is a Ye in life
and a ghost of Ye in death.
Her life should have been used
to support the Ye family.
What you said was exactly
what she should have done.
She should have lived
by the Ye family's rules,
but she refused.
She showed no respect
for her mother-in-law or her elders.
What's worse, she wanted
to invite even greater trouble.
But she left.
She signed a divorce agreement
and cut all ties with your Ye family.
Why couldn't you let her leave?
Leave?
She never left.
She was hiding at Zhengyi Temple
on the capital outskirts,
refusing to leave.
I know what you're up to.
You still wanted to come back.
She still wanted to seduce
Wenhua with her charm.
You wanted to drag the Ye family down
to the underworld as your scapegoat.
How could I let you go?
And how could I let her live?
So,
you killed her?
So what if I did?
It's only natural and proper for me
to clean up the mess from my family.
Now, let's settle this debt.
(Ye Mansion)
Open up!
We are Jingzhao Prefecture.
Search separately!
Stop.
(Mom,)
when will the tree we planted grow up?
When you grow up, it will shelter you
from the wind and rain.
Guards!
Li!
No.
Murder!
Li! Li! Li!
Li!
No!
Murder!
Li, no!
Li!
Murder!
No!
Li, my legs hurt so much!
Come and help me.
Don't kill...
Don't kill me!
Li.
It's okay.
Get in the carriage.
Your Highness,
the fish may have slipped away.
Let's go.
Physician, take care.
Farewell.
Mom.
I am Wenshen. I'm back.
I'm back.
The physician says
your wound is fine
and you will be fine soon.
When you recover,
I'll take you to the Immortal Dwelling.
They say it's where immortals live.
The stream water is like colorful glass,
extremely beautiful.
Why are you here?
Your Highness.
Your Highness, don't you
have anything to ask me?
If I ask, will you tell me the truth?
Her Highness told me
to answer truthfully
to any question you ask.
What if I don't ask?
Porridge. Hot porridge.
Hot porridge with dates and chestnuts.
Your Highness.
Her Highness has great stamina.
She's been out running recently.
It is already the eighth lap for today.
I told you to keep an eye
on the Ye family.
Any abnormalities these past few days?
Madam Ye is ill. It must be serious.
The children from out of town
have all returned.
Her Highness has gone back.
Go.
Your Highness,
you're finally back! You...
Your Highness! Your Highness, terrible!
Your Highness.
White banners are hung
in front of the Ye Mansion.
Madam Ye has passed away.
Li, are you there?
Yes.
Your Highness, why are you here?
What's the matter?
What happened?
Your grandmother has passed.
Since she got hit by a tree
on her birthday,
she has been bedridden.
Her condition deteriorated last night.
After suffering all night,
she still couldn't make it.
I need to go back to the Ye Mansion.
You have trouble walking. Please stay.
I'll have our sister-in-law
accompany me.
You'll go to her funeral?
Of course.
She's my grandmother,
my close kin.
We are bound by blood.
Now she's passed away.
How can I be absent?
The funeral must be taken seriously.
I need to bring more things back.
Incense, paper money, candles,
seasonal fruits,
wine, tea,
and some flowers for the spirit tablet.
All must be prepared.
And eternal lamps.
Nine lamps are suitable.
But I wonder
where to buy them at this hour.
Qingyu!
(Ye Mansion)
(Sacred Tablet
of the Late Mother, Ye Cenying)
Why hasn't Ye Li come yet?
Did you send someone to inform her?
Why told her to come back?
She's nothing but a jinx.
Ever since she returned
from Lishan Mountain,
Mother has been delirious,
and even doesn't recognize us anymore.
She's the one who caused Mother's death,
committing the heinous crime.
If she returns,
I will open the ancestral hall
and get the punishment rod.
Master Wending.
Princess Ding has arrived.
How dare you to come back?
Why wouldn't I dare to come back?
You ungrateful wretch!
You caused your grandmother's death,
violating human ethics,
unacceptable by both moral and law.
How dare you to stand before her coffin?
I caused her death?
Father, you were also
in the courtyard that night.
You saw it with your own eyes.
That night, a thunderbolt struck down
a tree and hit Grandmother,
causing her severe injuries and death.
This is a natural disaster.
What does it have to do with me?
Father, say something.
Ye Li!
You ungrateful wretch!
I will now punish you
on behalf of the ancestors.
I...
- Wending!
- I...
This is a funeral hall.
Let Mom leave in peace.
A false charge needs no true reason.
What now? Uncle Wending,
do you want to kill me
to avenge Grandmother?
Just stop it.
- Move!
- I...
How dare you!
After all, you are an official.
The Ye family is a scholarly
and upright household.
You should be well-versed in the laws.
If you have evidence, report it
to Jingzhao Prefecture for a trial.
If not,
stop slandering an innocent person
with a false charge.
Do you have anything else to say?
If not, I'll see Grandmother off
for the last time.
The gods
bear witness above.
(Preview)
I want you to take a walk with me.
Take a walk?
I'm a cripple.
Then I'll push you.
Alright.
If you stand up, you can try
to take a couple of steps forward.
I never thought I could stand up again.
You healed my legs.
Li.
Thank you.
How many more times
will you say thank you?
♪Memories hold you back
from fulfilling your dreams♪
♪Only by moving forward
can you find reunion♪
♪Endings only mark new routes♪
♪It's all part of the scenery♪
♪To the horizon's call♪
♪Your journey hasn't started♪
♪Towards mountains,
chase the stars bright♪
♪Both joy and grief
make the trip worthwhile♪
♪Trying to catch up
to your own lost shadow♪
♪Within the wilds, echoes thrive♪
♪Clear mind leads to a clear path♪
♪Be grateful to your losses♪
♪Make your steps weightless♪
♪Towards mountains,
chase the stars bright♪
♪Let time embrace you
and wash away the past♪
♪Put every twist behind you,
drift leisurely through time♪
♪Make headway against the wind,
let mountains bow to your pace♪
♪Rush towards a life without regret♪
♪Let your nature burst free♪
♪Unbound by form♪